POOJAN PATEL

≥ poojanpatel182@gmail.com

9664779818

in LinkedIn

GitHub

Profile

I'm a Software Developer located in India. I have a serious passion for animations and creating intuitive, dynamic user experiences. I have worked with Frontend as well as Backend languages. With a strong emphasis on "Progressive Enhancement", I look for creative ways to push the boundaries of website's code without compromising on browser support. I'm determined to advance in my job and pick up new skills in order to keep up with the latest developments in technology and to help the company succeed.

Professional Experience

Subject Matter Expert

November 2023 – present | Remote

Chegg India

- As a computer science expert, I need to solve questions asked by college students on the platform.
- The Chegg platform provides products and services to support learners to help them better understand their academic course materials, and also provides personal and professional development skills training.
- Providing accurate solutions step by step and getting qualtiy feedback.
- Participating in webinars and learning new aspects in the respective field.

Intern

January 2024 – present | Anand, Gujarat

Tech Elecon

- As a Trainee, I gained a solid understanding of React's core concepts, including components, state, and props. Learning how to create reusable UI components for building scalable applications.
- Exploring the lifecycle of software development and preparing various documentations.
- Currently, working on project known as Asset management to montior, optimize and manage the company's property.
- By replacing manual paper-based systems or outdated methods with digital solutions, these systems aim to enhance security, improve operational efficiency, and create a seamless experience for staff members.

Intern

May 2023 – June 2023 | Anand, Gujarat

TechnoGuide Infosoft Pvt. Ltd. \Box

- As a Frontend and Backend Developer, I've implemented the development of the VISA CRM system, a consultancy platform designed to assist students, faculty, and counselors in their study abroad journeys.
- Student Module: I've crafted the user-friendly interface for students, making it easy for them to access crucial information and check their VISA application status hassle-free.
- Counselor Module: I've worked on the Counselor Module, empowering counselors to provide expert guidance to students, including college recommendations and tailored advice.
- Admin Module: I've also contributed to the Admin Module, ensuring smooth system management and enhancing the user experience for administrators.

Intern

May 2022 – July 2022 | Anand, Gujarat

KERYAR 🗆

- Implemented the development of Salon Management Website to automate the products and range of services provided by the salon.
- Product Management: Effortlessly add and manage salon products and supplies.
- Services Listing: Maintain a comprehensive list of services offered.
- Invoice Generation: Streamline billing and invoice generation for clients.
- Additional features, which I cannot disclose due to confidentiality of the company.

Education

B.Tech, Computer Engineering

Charotar University of Science and Technology

8.15 CGPA

Higher Secondary (CBSE)

Kendriya Vidhyalaya

84.2 %

April 2008 – May 2020 | Anand, Gujarat

May 2020 - present | Changa, Gujarat

Secondary (CBSE)

Kendriya Vidhyalaya

91.6%

April 2008 - May 2020 | Anand, Gujarat

Projects

Django Authentication

May 2023

Secure User Management Made Easy

The goal of the project is to learn the customize authentication of Login and Signup.

- --> It is developed based on Django, MySQL, Bootstrap & HTML/CSS.
- --> It provides the authentication of Login form fields such as name, email & password.

User Registration: Allow users to create accounts with a few simple steps, collecting essential information.

Login and Logout: Provide a secure login system with session management for a smooth user experience.

Hackers Arcade

August 2023 – December 2023

Cybersecurity learning platform

The purpose of building this project is to provide an online platform to individuals that offers a range of cyber security challenges, including vulnerable machines, CTF (Capture the Flag) challenges, and more.

My duty as a frontend developer is to design and implement the user interface and integrate it with the backend.

- --> It is developed using ReactJS as frontend and Django & python shell scripting as its backend.
- --> It provides features like Admin Dashboard to manage the users & machines, User registration & Login, Vulnerable Machines, Educational Blogs.
- -->After logging in, it displays their profile of the user along with vulnerable machines that user has an access to for practice and educational resources are available.

VISA CRM June 2023 – present

Automate the VISA Consultancy

The goal is to automate the whole VISA consultancy Program.

- --> It is developed based on CodeIgniter (PHP) and Django.
- --> It provides features like Visa & College Application Details. It also recommends colleges according to country in which you are going to study or settle. There are many features of this project but as it is company confidentiality I cannot disclose. It is still under development cycle.

Certificates

The Web Developer Bootcamp

2023 🖸

Advanced understanding of Frontend & Backend Applications

JavaScript Essentials ☑ Basic Understanding of

Fundamentals of JavaScript

Skills

HTML (Experienced) • **CSS** (Experienced) • **JavaScript** (Experienced) • **AngularJS** (Beginner)

ReactJS (Experienced) • CodeIgniter (Skillful) • Django (Beginner) • PHP (Beginner) • NodeJs (Skillful)

MySQL (Beginner) • MongoDB (Beginner) • ExpressJS (Beginner) • Python (Beginner) • C (basic)

C++ (Skillful) • MySQL (Skillful) • Bootstrap (Experienced) • Tailwind CSS (Experienced)

Postman (Beginner) • Java (Beginner) • Github (Skillful) • Github (Skillful) • Figma (Beginner)

Languages

Gujarati

Full working Proficiency

English

Highly Proficient in Speaking and Writing

Hindi

Full working proficiency